Guide to the J. Martin Evans Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Administration
  - Humanities and Sciences Associate Dean Letters (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Humanities and Sciences Associate Dean Letters (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - English Department Material (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - English Department Chair Correspondence (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - English Department Chair Correspondence (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Humanities and Sciences Salary Raises (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Western Culture Family Symposium (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - English, 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Contains a copy of the Report of the Commission on Undergraduate Education (1994); undergraduate and graduate student survey results from the English Department (1996-1997); copy of a report from a department meeting (May 1997, "Rethinking Undergraduate Studies in English"); personal e-mails; handwritten notes.
  - Old A.P. Business, 1975-1986; Contains professional correspondence, meeting notes, and hand-written notes from business related to the Appointments and Promotions (A&P) Committee. Opinions section from an October 27, 1975 copy of The Stanford Daily. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Contains report on curriculum for 1998-99; copy of template letter to assistant professors on course scheduling; hand-written notes.
  - Grad Quals Questions, 1983-2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Contains materials related to qualifying examinations.
  - Western Culture (1 of 2), 1986-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Contains professional correspondence, newspaper articles, and logistical materials related to the Western Culture Program.
  - Western Culture (2 of 2), 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Contains a collection of news articles and correspondence related to the Western Culture Program.
  - Student Files, 1994-2011
    Contains student files from English 162: Critical Methods; course syllabus from Literary Criticism and Literary Texts: The Anglo-American Tradition; student essays.
  - Itinerary - Fynes Moryson (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Contains Part 1 of "Itinerary" by Fynes Moryson.
  - Travel (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Contains mementos from travel to England and Italy; pamphlets, postcards, photographs, and notes.
  - Travel (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Contains books; "Historical Atlas of the World"; "The Marble Pavement of the Cathedral of Siena"; "Literary Cities of Italy".
  - Tenure, 1979-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Contains newspaper articles related to academic tenure.
  - Press on Allen, Kennedy, Dornbusch, 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Contains articles from The Stanford Daily and the San Francisco Chronicle related to Dean Lucille A. Allen’s terminal leave of absence and Associate Professor H. Bruce Franklin’s dismissal from the English Department; professional correspondence.
  - General Education, 1976-2008 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Contains news articles related to instruction in liberal education and the humanities; defense of the humanities from Stanford professors in response to Stanley Fish; letter to President Donald Kennedy and Provost James Rosse from the Area One Program Committee (The Program in Cultures, Ideas, and Values) regarding hiring of faculty.
  - Miscellaneous Ideas and Projects, 1975-1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Contains newspaper articles; hand-written notes; correspondence; questions for Dean Evans submitted by members of the Humanities 353 colloquium (1978); draft of "The Unfinished Renaissance of the Humanities" by Professor William Clebsch (1978); materials from the Commission on the Humanities (1979).
  - Interview with Evans, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Milton
  - Misc. Abstracts (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondance (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Vol. 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Vol. 1 Rejects (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Vol. 2 Rejects (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Vol. 3 Rejects (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Quest of Seth, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Lycidas and the Dolphins (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lycidas, Daphnis, Gallus (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Some Versions of the Fall, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Heirs of Fame (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Moral Fiction in Milton and Spencer (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Milton Studies XV (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Matter of Glory (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Milton's Aristocratic Entertainments (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - The Humanism of Paradise Lost (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Milton and the Transformation of Ancient Epic (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Milton and the Science of Saints (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Lycidas and the Italian Critics (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Milton and his Epic Tradition (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Recapitulated Fall (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Microcosmic Adam (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Genesis B and it's Background (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Petrarch Ascent of Mt. Ventoux (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Aemelia Lanyer, Salve Red Judaeorum (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Genesis A-B (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Seneca, On Providence (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bibliography PL (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Genesis ii-iii (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Aeneid Passage (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Obsequies to the memorie of Mr. Edward King (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Chronology-Milton (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Dramatic Drafts of PL (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - The Cessation of the Oracles (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Bibliography - Nativity Ode (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Felix Culpa Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Adam lay ibounden etc. (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Calvinism vs. Arminianism (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Marriage Tests (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Misc. Milton 1 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Virgil's Fourth Eclogue (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Misc. Biblio Milton (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Misc. Milton 2 (Box 6A, Folder 43)
  - The Birth of the Author (Box 6A, Folder 44)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Draft A) (Box 6A, Folder 45)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Draft B) (Box 6A, Folder 46)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Draft C) (Box 6A, Folder 47)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Press) (Box 6A, Folder 48)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Colleague's Comments) (Box 6A, Folder 49)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Draft D) (Box 6A, Folder 49)
  - The Miltonic Moment (Draft E) (Box 6A, Folder 50)
  - Milton Article and Music Notes, Contains article from The New Yorker, "Return to Paradise: The enduring relevance of John Milton"; musical notes from "The Masque of Comus", composed by Henry Lawes. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Milton-Agency Node, Contains draft, "Poetic Agency: The Poems of Mr. John Milton". (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Lycidas - Notes, Contains outline, script, and notes on "Lycidas" by John Milton; outline, "The Conventions of Pastoral Elegy"; "Lycidas" resources; copies of "From Obsequies to the Memorie of Mr. Edward King--Opening Poem by Henry King"; clipping, "The Reason of Church Government"; "Lycidas - A Eulogistic Review" by J.M. Evans; "Outline: Virgil's Eclogue X and the Pastoral Elegy"; excerpt from Theocritus. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lycidas in Tusta, Trinity, Contains writings on John Milton's poems. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Majestik Milton (Box 6A, Folder 51)
  - Milton's Imperial Epic (Box 6A, Folder 52)
  - Various Reviews (Box 6A, Folder 53)
  - Lycidas (Box 6A, Folder 54)
  - Grief and English Elegy, 1986 Aug (Box 6A, Folder 55)
  - Melodious Tears (Box 6A, Folder 57)
  - John Milton: Poet, Priest, Prophet (Box 6A, Folder 58)
  - Milton and Augustine (Box 6A, Folder 59)
  - Surrey: The Means to Attain Happy Life (Box 6A, Folder 60)
  - Paradise Lost - Plans (Box 6A, Folder 61)
  - Agency - Milton "Lycidas" (Box 6A, Folder 62)
  - Agency + Milton No Lycidas (Box 6A, Folder 63)
  - PL Plans - Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 64)
  - PL Garden + Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 65)
  - Fair Infant (Box 6A, Folder 66)
  - PL Hell - Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 67)
  - PL Lycidas - Notes (Box 6A, Folder 68)
  - PL Theology - Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 69)
  - PL Heaven - Notes (Box 6A, Folder 70)
  - Paradise Regained - Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 71)
  - PL Heaven - Criticism (Box 6A, Folder 72)
  - Satan (Box 6A, Folder 73)
  - Current [Criticism], 1970 (Box 6A, Folder 74)
  - Vol. 2 (Box 6A, Folder 75)
  - Vol. 3 (Box 6A, Folder 76)
  - Vol. 4 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Vol. 4 Rejects (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Vol. 5 Rejects (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Photographic Slides
  - Dore Slides (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Martin Slides (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cheron Slides (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Medina Slides (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Hayman Slides (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Aldritch/Facetti/Lens Slides (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Computer files, 216 megabyte(s); (902 files in 46 directories)